あの…
良介兄さん。
Not Quite Open Yet!
どうすんだ、内定者面談？ 先輩怒ってたぞ。
旅先からばっくれたうえに、朝帰りとはなー。
卒業旅行ってぇのは、
学生気分を置いてくるための旅行じゃなかったのかー？
事故とかなくてよかったよ。
Sangetsu Breads
早く避難しろー。
朝子に見つかったらどやされるぞー。
Welcome to
Sangetsu Breads!
A dying scream makes no sound
We live a dying dream...
Not only did you change your travel plans,
you stayed out all night too.
Callin' out to all that I've ever known
Ryousuke...
Here am I, lost and found...
If you know what I mean...
Aren't graduation trips for bidding farewell to your time as a student?
It's all that I've ever known...
Callin' out to all
What are you going to do about your interview?
It's all that I've ever known
My ex-colleagues were pretty angry.
Catch the wheel that breaks a butterfly
Um...
I'm glad that you weren't in an accident or anything like that.
Hide, quickly.
Cry the rain that fills the ocean wide
Asako will smack you when she finds you.
I tried to talk with God to no avail
EPISODE 4
Real Reality
Fictional Reality
http://animetranscripts.wikispaces.com
Calling him up in-and-out of nowhere
Losing your memories is really inconvenient...
記憶がないって、ホント不便だよな。
I said if you won't save me
Please don't waste my time
Did I really kill twenty thousand NEETs?
俺さ、二万人のニート… 殺したの？
申し訳ありません。
My humble apologies,
but we do not know what happened to them.
彼らのその後については把握しておりません。
でも、俺がここに二万人のニートを集めてたのは事実なんだろ？
But it's true that I gathered twenty thousand NEETs together, right?
Indeed.
はい。
マジかよ～。やっぱやってんのかな～？
Is this for real...
--Akira
--kill you!
Guess I really did it...
あとさ、なんで俺がセレソンなんてのに選ばれたの？
Also, why was I selected to become a Selecao?
I wonder.
さあ？ セレソン選抜の基準をジュイスは聞かされておりませんので。
Juiz wasn't informed about the criteria used to select a Selecao.
そう、聞かされてないんだ？
I see, you weren't told.
はい。
Indeed.
Finally, what's this "Supporter" thing?
じゃあさ、サポーターってのは何？
The Supporter is a system whereby one of the twelve Selecao
サポーターというのは12人のセレソンの中の一人で、
is given the task to eliminate those Selecao who are no longer fit to act as Saviors.
救世主に不適格なセレソンを排除する役目を担うシステムのことです。
それが俺だってこと？
Is that me?
I wonder.
さあ？ それもジュイスにはちょっと…
Juiz wasn't really informed of that either.
要するに、ジュイスに俺のこと聞いてもムダってわけだ？
In other words, it's pointless to ask you anything about myself.
Yes, indeed.
はい、その通りです。
じゃあ、誰に聞けっつの？！
少しは俺の身になってくれよ。
Then who should I ask?!
Try to sympathize a bit with me here.
Oh yeah, that old man told me to ask another Selecao.
そういやあのオッサン、他のセレソンに聞けって言ってたな。
Selecao Activity History
Refresh
History
Delete
Balance:
Support to
Sasai Hirofumi
Chuo Social Insurance
Medical Care Consultation
Board  Middleman
Insurance office Medical Care Officer
Introduction
Balance:
Reception for technical officer
via alumni association
Balance:
What's going on?
何だこれ。ほとんど分刻みで実行されてんぞ。
All these seem to have been requested in one minute intervals.
Did Number 5 make those requests one right after another?
五番の奴、休みなく申請続けてんの？
いいえ。私たちはややこしい申請の場合、
He didn't.
When we receive a complicated request,
we break them down into smaller tasks before we execute them.
案件をいくつかの条件に分けて実行していくんです。
じゃあこれって、元は一つの申請？
This was originally one request?
Chuo Social Insurance
Medical Care Consultation
Board  Middleman
Insurance office Medical
Care Officer Introduction
Selecao Activity History
Refresh
History
Delete
Balance:
Insurance office Medical
Care Officer Introduction
Reception for technical
officer via alumni
association
Hey, Juiz.
なあ、ジュイス。東洋メディカルテックって会社から、
Reception for technical
officer via alumni
association
IPP Policy Research
Group Contribution
Can you help me find out who bought an MRI machine two days ago from Touyou Medical Tech?
IPP Policy Research
Group Contribution
Group to Support
Dr. Shoda Hiroto  Party
Ogawa Akihiro
Election Office
Support Visit
おとといＭＲＩを納入した先を調べてくれるかな？
Ogawa Akihiro
Election Office
Support Visit
Group to Reelect
Assemblyman Sanada
Yuji  Party
Group to Reelect
Assemblyman Sanada
Yuji  Party
Evaluation board member
reception
Aiji U. Alumni Assoc. Gunma
Pref. Regional Division
Federated Special General
Aiji U. Alumni Assoc. Gunma
Pref. Regional Division
Federated Special General
Oyanagi Ken'ichi
Election Countermeasures
HQ Chief  Support Visit
Oyanagi Ken'ichi
Election Countermeasures
HQ Chief  Support Visit
Mayoral Primary Funds
Murata Seiji
Request accepted.
受理されました。今後も救世主たらんことを。
Mayoral Primary Funds
Murata Seiji
Funds Managment Group
"Shuko-Kai"  CAO
Please continue your work as a Savior.
Funds Managment Group
"Shuko-Kai"  CAO
Former JMA Executive
Director/Uchida Kei, Hirai
Tokuro, Motobaku
Toyo Medical Tech
MRI System Pay
Exit
Road Closed
Exit Here
The missile impact site?
ミサイルの爆心地…
Hey, that's dangerous!
おい！ 危ないだろう！
Damn it, didn't you see the signpost?
…ったく！ 標識見えなかったんですかねえ？
I thought he was going to dump his bike.
あのままバイクを放り捨てるのかと思ったよ。
Like in that movie.
あの映画みたいにさ。
What are you talking about?
何ですかそれ？
There used to be a movie like that.
昔あったんだよ。
ラストシーンでスクーターを放り捨てる青春映画が。
It's a coming-of-age movie where, in the last scene, a scooter was dumped.
Don't you know the title of that movie?
知らない？ あの映画のタイトル。
I don't really watch coming-of-age movies these days.
今どき青春映画なんて見ませんからねえ。
そうなの？
Is that so?
Johnny!
ジョニー？！
Johnny! Johnny!
ジョニー！ ジョニー！
やめろ！
Stop it, you bastards!
こいつ！ いい加減にしろ！
Cut it out!
こーのー、役立たずどもがあ～！
You useless fools!
Hey, are you okay?
おい、だいじょぶか、お前？
さらば青春の光。
Quadrophenia.
The title of the movie that you were talking about earlier.
さっき言って、た映画のタイトル。
Ah, that's the name! Quadrophenia!
ああ、そうだっ！ さらば青春の光！
Don't think that I'm like him.
あんなのと一緒にしないでよね。
俺、別にいま絶望してないから。
I don't feel depressed right now.
関越道ってどう行くんだっけ？
How do I reach the Kan-Etsu Expressway?
Is that right?
そうなの。
で、結局帰ってきたの今朝だったみたいで。
In the end, it looks like she only returned this morning.
Yes, it seems that she stayed over at Micchon's place last night.
そう。昨日はみっちょんとこに泊めてもらったみたいよ。
咲！ 大杉くんから電話。
そろそろ起きなさいよ
Saki, Oosugi-kun's on the phone.
It's time for you to wake up.
起きてる。
I'm awake.
He was worried and has called several times.
心配して何度も電話くれたんだよ。
Hello?
もしもし？
Sorry, were you asleep?
ごめん、寝てた？
ううん。こっちこそ連絡しなくて…
Nope. I should be the one apologizing for not calling you.
Self-Development Corner
It's okay, as long as you're safe.
いや、無事だったらいいんだ。
昨日、みっちょんとこ泊まったの？
You stayed over at Micchon's place last night?
Yeah.
うん。
Oh...
I see.
そう。ところで、面談はどうなった？
By the way, how was your interview?
明日、改めて会ってもらえることになった
I'm having another one tomorrow.
よかった。それじゃあさ、一緒に出ない？
That's great.
Why don't we go there together?
僕も明日から内定者研修なんだ。
It's my job induction tomorrow too.
Our offices aren't near each other, right?
遠回りでしょ？
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It'll be fine.
You'll feel helpless during the interview, right?
面談とかって心細いじゃない？
誰か一緒の方が勇気出るし。
You'll be able to pluck up your courage if someone is there with you.
うん。ありがとう。
Yeah, thanks.
じゃあ、明日。
See you tomorrow then.
At Micchon's place...
みっちょんとこって…
I went home without saying anything this
morning, but did something happen?  It
seemed like your lost memories came back,
but I'm sending you a text because I'm still
worried.  Please reply when you have the time.
I went home without saying anything this
morning, but did something happen?  It
seemed like your lost memories came back,
but I'm sending you a text because I'm still
worried.  Please reply when you have the time.
I went home without saying anything this
morning, but did something happen?  It
seemed like your lost memories came back,
but I'm sending you a text because I'm still
worried.
New Mail
Takizawa Akira
I went home without saying anything this
morning, but did something happen?
It seemed like your lost memories
came back, but I'm sending you a
text because I'm still worried.
Message Sent
What am I doing?
何やってんだろ…
Hiura General Hospital
Reception
すいません。
昨日こちらの病院でＭＲＩっていう機械を買ったと思うんですけど、
Excuse me.
Reception
There should be someone from this hospital who bought an MRI machine yesterday.
Do you know who that might be?
それ買ったのって誰ですかね？
Even though you ask "who"...
誰…と言われましても。
まあ、あえて言えば、
At a guess, it was probably the director.
院長先生ということになるんでしょうか。
なるほど。それじゃあ、申し訳ないんだけど、
その院長先生に取り次いでもらえますか？
I see.
Well, sorry for being rude, but can you take me to the director?
失礼ですが、アポイントは…
Sorry, but do you have an appointment...?
I don't.
いやぁ、ないんですけど。
セレソンが来てるって言ってもらえれば、たぶん。
He'll understand if you tell him that a Selecao is here.
これ、携帯の番号です。
This is my cellphone number.
なんか、爺さん、婆さんばっかだな。
For some reason, this place is filled with old folks.
Tonan Financial
Asauri Weekly
Weekly Literature Plan
Special: The Dark Shadows of Regional Medicine
Tonan Financial
Chief Physician Hiura Hajime
Former genius brain surgeon
30 billion yen!!
Funding from an
unknown source
Mysteriously Inauguration As Local Medical
Association President Within 1 Year of Opening Practice
Rumors of Bribery Spreading
to the Prefectural Assembly
Is the Prefectural Assembly working
for the Profit of a Private Hospital?
こんなもん読まんでいい。
Don't read such things.
Dr. Hiura is a savior to us.
ワシらにとって、火浦先生は救世主なんだ。
No matter what others say about him.
誰が何と言おうとな。
Savior?
救世主？
Morimi Saki
Morimi Saki?
森美咲。
Hello?
もしもし?
So, you're the Selecao?
セレソンというのは君かね？
ああ、俺、滝沢っていいます。
Ah, my name is Takizawa.
どうやってここを突き止めた？
How did you find this place?
ええと…履歴にあったＭＲＩって機械の納入先を調べて…
There were records in the logs about a MRI machine, so I investigated where it was delivered to.
Which number are you?
君のナンバーはいくつだ？
I'm sorry?
はい？
君は何番目のセレソンかね？
What's your Selecao number?
Number 9.
九番です。
なるほど…九番がサポーターだったか。
I see.
Wasn't Number 9 the Supporter?
ちょっと待ってください！
Hold on a minute.
近藤のオッサンにもそう言われたんですけど、
Old man Kondou said the same thing.
But what's that all about?
それって何なんですか？
近藤とは、４番のことかね？
Kondou was Number 4, right?
Yeah.
Hey, can we meet up face-to-face to talk?
あの、直接会って話しません？
It seems that I've erased my own memories.
俺、自分で自分の記憶消しちゃったらしくて、
何も思い出せないんです。
I don't remember anything.
Nothing about this cellphone, Selecao or this game that we seem to be participating in.
この携帯のことも、セレソンとか、
俺たちが参加しているらしいゲームのこととかも。
だから、その辺のことを教えてほしいだけで。
I just want you to tell me about them.
お願いしますよ！
Please.
君の殺されるのは構わない。それがルールならな。
I don't care if you kill me, if that's part of the rules.
However, I'm reluctant to die when I still have money left.
だが、残金のあるうちに殺されるのは不本意だ。
いや…殺さないし。
Err, I won't kill you...
Well, fine then.
ま、いいだろう。今から薬を持って行かせる。
I'll get someone to bring some medicine to you.
その薬を飲めば、
君がどうやってその携帯を手に入れたのかは分かるはずだよ
Take the medicine and you'll know how you got that cellphone.
あの…ちなみにその薬って何の薬なんですか？
Um, just what sort of medicine is it?
Who knows.
さあな。
はやっ！ 考える余地はないってことですか？
That was fast!
Don't I get time to think?
I'll take it.
飲みますよ。
医者が病院で毒盛るか、普通…？
Do doctors usually give poison in a hospital?
まったく…とんでもねえ医者だな。
Damn it, what a reckless doctor.
Greetings, this is Mr. Outside.
ごきげんよう。Mr.OUTSIDEだ。
Mr.OUTSIDE？
Mr. Outside?
私は至極個人的な信念に基づき、
Guided strongly by my own beliefs,
I've self-righteously selected twelve people to become Saviors to save this country.
この国を救うための救世主を十二人、
独善的に選抜することに決めた。
These twelve people will be called "Selecao."
そしてその12人をセレソンと名付け、
さらにそのうちの一人をサポーターに任命した。
In addition, one of the twelve will be appointed to be the "Supporter."
君は今日からセレソンだ。おめでとう。
You're a Selecao from now on.
Congratulations.
By the way, the Supporter can be considered as the twelfth player in the game.
ちなみにサポーターとは、いわゆる12番目の選手…
He'll assist you as much as he can and,
at the same time, observe you without scruples...
熱狂的な応援者であり、冷酷な監視員のことだ。
The moment you cease to be fit to be a Selecao,
もし君がセレソンとして正しく機能しなかった場合は、
you should expect to receive harsh judgment from the Supporter.
サポーターによって厳しくジャッジが下されると思ってくれたまえ。
So, I'm not the Supporter?
じゃあ、俺はサポーターじゃないんだ？
I'm the only one who knows who of the twelve players is the Supporter.
十二人のうち、誰がサポーターかは私しか知らない。
君かも知れないし、違うかもしれない。
It might be you, and it might not be you.
なお、選別された12人からは、身に覚えがあろうとなかろうと、
The twelve chosen players very much wanted to be Selecao, whether they remember that or not.
セレソンになろうという強い意志があったと認識している。
That is why you are not allowed to refuse this mission.
したがって、この使命を辞退することは許されない。
As a present, your cellphone has been charged with ten billion yen.
プレゼントした携帯の中には100 億円が入っている。
You are free to use it however you like.
使い道は全面的に君に任せる。
自由な発想でこの国を正しき方向に導いてほしい。
You are free to express your ideas, and I hope that you will use them to lead this country down the proper path.
ただし、その100億を現金に換えることはできない。
However, that ten billion yen cannot be cashed out.
Press the center button if you have any requests.
何らかの要望が生じた場合、
中央のボタンを押してコンシェルジュを呼び出してもらえれば
Your concierge will be summoned, and they will be able to deal with them at any time.
いつでも対応するようになっている。
Whatever expenses incurred due to this will be deducted from the ten billion yen.
なお、その際にかかる費用は 100億円から引き落とされ、
Your usage will be recorded in the logs, and the other Selecao will be notified of this.
その使用履歴は他のセレソンに通知されるものとする。
最後にペナルティについて伝えておく。
Finally, I'll talk about the penalties involved.
If any of these conditions are met, the Selecao must be prepared for imminent death at the Supporter's hands:
以下の条件が該当するセレソンは、サポーターによって迅速かつ
確実な死が与えられると思ってほしい。
One: Abandoning your mission halfway through or planning to run away from it.
第一に、任務を途中放棄し、逃亡を図った場合。
Two: Not using your cellphone for an extended period of time or being unable to achieve any results.
第二に、携帯を長期にわたって使用せず、
何の成果も得られない場合。
Three: Continually using the ten billion you were given for personal benefit, instead of national interest.
第三に、与えられた100億を国益のためでなく、
個人の欲望のために使用し続けた場合。
Four: Your balance reaches zero and yet, you fail to save the country.
第四に、国を救うという目的が果たせぬまま、
残高がゼロになった場合である。
ただし、これらは最低限の事項にすぎない。
This is just the bare minimum of information.
I hope that those who were selected to be responsible for their own actions will act to the best of their abilities.
選ばれし者はその行動に極力責任を持ってもらいたい。
なお、十二人のセレソンのうち最終的に生き残れるのは
Out of the twelve Selecao, the only one to survive will be the one who completes their mission first.
最初に使命を全うした一人に限られる。
Once someone reaches the goal, the rest will be eliminated.
誰かがゴールした時点で残りのセレソンは自動的に消滅する。
What's up with that?
何だよ、それ！ 参加そのものが罰ゲームじゃんか！
You're already incurring a penalty just by entering the game.
私からは以上だ。
That's all I have to say.
もし君がうまい具合にこの国を救う方法を見出し、
If you succeed in finding a way to save this country, you'll win and consequently meet me.
最初にゴールした暁には、
自然に私の元にたどり着くようになっている。
Noblesse Oblige.
ノブレス・オブリージュ。君が救世主たらんことを切に願う…
Please continue your work as a Savior.
Hiura-san, was this what it was like when you received your cellphone?
火浦さんも、この携帯もらった時、こんなんだったんですか？
It was a bit dramatic, wasn't it?
少々芝居がかってしまったがね。
どうしてこんなマネを…
Why are you doing this?
I wanted to live until my requests were approved at the prefecture assembly today.
今日の県議会で私の要望が通るまでは生きていたくてね。
君がサポーターだった場合を恐れ、眠ってもらった。
I was afraid that you were the Supporter, so I made you take a nap.
That was basically what happened.
あれで大体合っているはずだ。
I was drunk that day, and got in a taxi.
あの日、酔ってタクシーに乗り、
気づいたらゲロにまみれて奇妙な箱と対面していた。
When I woke up, I was covered in vomit and saw a weird box.
ゲロまで再現しなくても…
You didn't have to reproduce the vomiting bit too.
Higura-san, do you know if you joined this game of your own free will?
で、火浦さんには、
自ら望んでゲームに参加したって心当たりは？
I didn't. Or perhaps you could say that I did.
ない。が、あるといえばある。
For a long time now, I've been feeling my limitations as a neurosurgeon.
私はもうずいぶん前から
脳外科医としての自分に限界を感じていてね。
The number of people a doctor can save in his life is limited.
所詮、
一人の医師が生涯で救うことのできる命の数はたかが知れている。
見たまえ。
Take a look.
They can also work here.
この街に患者を集めると同時に、
家族にも転居してもらい、
うちで雇用できるよう法律を変えさせた
I changed the law so that patients can gather in this town, and at the same time,
their families can move here to work.
単純な話さ。
It's very simple.
国が切り捨てようとした高齢者を
I used the ten billion to create a private hospital,
where the senior citizens who were abandoned by the country can be employed.
人的資源として雇用できる個人病院を
百億かけて作ったってことさ。
My work here is done once the system becomes capable of operating autonomously.
後はそのシステムが自治体によって運営されるようにできれば
私の仕事は終わる。
Balance:
Switch
Display
Function
High-Technology Research
Personnel Training Cen--
Establishment of
medical-industry
investment fund
Commencing regenerative
medicine in the
Medical Industry City
今までの履歴、賄賂だったんですか？
Everything in your logs so far were bribes?
Juiz is incredible.
ジュイスは優秀だな。
She was able to persuade the entire prefectural assembly in such a short amount of time.
この短期間に県議会をすべて丸め込んだんだからな。
Juiz? Wait...
ジュイスが？ 待てよ…
ってことは、他のセレソンは俺も含めて消滅する…？
Does that mean that the other Selecao, including me, will be eliminated now?
No, that probably won't happen.
いや、それはないだろう。
ここはあくまで私個人が理想とする病院だからね。
This is ultimately just a hospital that was created based on my own ideals.
It probably doesn't fit in with Outside's view.
アウトサイドの眼鏡には適ってないだろう。
What should I do if this isn't enough to finish the game?
これで上がれないなら、後は何をすりゃいいんだよ？
Outside is quite the devil.
アウトサイドってのは悪魔だな…
I think that he's a generous god.
私には気前のいい神に思えるがね。
We got dragged into a troublesome game.
俺たち、厄介なゲームに巻き込まれましたね…
俺も死にたくはないけど、
I don't want to die,
but should I share half of my money with you?
俺のカネ半分そっちに分けましょうか？
Thanks for your concern.
心遣いには感謝するがね。
私は初めから上がるつもりはないんだ。
I had no intentions of finishing this game right from the start.
So? What else do you want to know?
…それで？ 君はあと何を聞きたいのかね？
I don't know what kind of person you are though.
君が何者かなんて私にも分からないよ。
What have I been doing up till now?
俺、いままで何やってました？
I've already used up around two billion.
たぶん、二十億くらい使ってるんですけど…
ゴーストタウンのショッピングモール。
A shopping mall in a ghost town.
500 sea containers.
海上コンテナ五百個。
Entertainment expenses for the Department of Foreign Affairs.
外務省の接待費。
You did various other things too.
他にも色々やっていたようだねえ。
Could it be that I committed mass murder...?
もしかして、大量殺人とか…？
Sorry, but I won't tell you anything else.
悪いが、教えるのはやめておくよ。
Why?
何でですか？！
君は記憶を消してまで何かをしようとしたんだろう？
You tried to do something by erasing your memories, right?
This is just speculation based on the logs, but Number 9 was quite charismatic before his memory loss.
履歴から察するに、
記憶を消す前の九番はなかなか魅力的な人物だった。
And yet you've abandoned your past and are pinning everything on your new self.
その君が、過去を捨ててまで新しい自分に賭けたんだ。
だったら、そのままの君でいいと思うがねえ。
That's why you should stay as you are now.
死ぬ前に会えてよかったよ。
It was great to meet you before I die.
Stop saying that!
やめてくださいよ！まだ…
You might still...
Please continue your work as a Savior.
君が救世主たらんことを。
This is Juiz.
ジュイスです。
やあ、ジュイス。色々と世話になったね。
Hi, Juiz. Thanks for all the help.
おかげで有意義な金の使い方ができたよ。
Thanks to you, I was able to use that money in a meaningful way.
Don't mention it.
とんでもない。たいしたお役にも立てなくて。
I wasn't able to help you much.
No, that was more than enough.
いや、充分だ。ありがとう。
Thanks.
You're the Supporter?
あなたがサポーターだったのか…
I'm ready.
覚悟はできている。悔いはない。
I have no regrets.
The Supporter is here?!
サポーターか？！
Hiura-san, you were too kind.
火浦さん、あんた人がよすぎるよ。
I just can't accept this.
俺は納得いかない。
My anger won't be curbed until I've punched the guy who gave me this screwed-up phone.
こんなふざけた携帯送りつけた奴、
ぶん殴ってやらなきゃ、気が済まないよ！
Hiura General Hospital
夜は封印
戸惑い混じれば終わる
迷い出すぐらいならいっそ
わ     け
理由も捨てよう
また夢に溺れる
不確かに続いてく未来
まだ君を許せる
意味を知れる
耳を澄ますための夜
その理由を真似て変われる
君の呼吸を知るために
未来の根を切っても構わない